<?xml version="1.0"?>
<VersionInfo>
    <VersionName>"3.3 'Glasgow'"</VersionName>
    <VersionNumber>"3.3.0"</VersionNumber>
    <DownloadLocation>"http://www.uoguelph.ca/~hydrogeo/Whitebox/download.shtml"</DownloadLocation>
    <DownloadArtifact>"http://www.uoguelph.ca/~hydrogeo/Whitebox/WhiteboxGAT.zip"</DownloadArtifact>
    <Announcements number="19">
        <Announcement>
            <Date>2016-05-20</Date>
            <Language>en</Language>
            <Title>Whitebox 3.3.0 Has Been Released</Title>
            <Message><![CDATA[<p>The following additions/modifications have been made:</p>
<ul>
<li>Altered the 'Update Script From Code Repository' function to retrieve updates 
 from the new GitHub Whitebox repo rather than Google Code.</li>
<li>Added the Quantiles tool, which transforms a raster into quantiles. Quantiles 
 are values taken at regular intervals from the inverse of the cumulative 
 distribution function (CDF) of a random variable.</li>
<li>Fixed a bug in the LAS2Shapefile tool that did not allow for the output dbf file
 to be written.</li>
<li>Added the Convert LAS to MultiPointZ Shapefile tool. This allows for a more
 efficient means of storing LiDAR data as a Shapefile. All LiDAR points are 
 stored in a single record in the Shapefile, with Z and intensity data stored
 in the 'z' and 'm' components of the shapefile respectively.</li>
<li>Added the Unnest Basins tool to extract the entire, unnested watersheds from 
 a series of pour points and a DEM.</li>
<li>Added the Stream Slope (continuous) tool, which calculates the slope of stream
 grid cells in a raster stream network.</li>
<li>Added the Rasterize Streams tool.</li>
<li>Added the Prune Vector Stream Network tool.</li>
<li>Added the experimental Impoundment Index tool for applications involving the
 mapping of drained wetlands from LiDAR and other fine-resolution DEMs.</li>
<li>Added the Roughness From Point Cloud Profiles (RPCP) tool.</li>
<li>Added the Split Vector Lines tool.</li>
<li>Added the Integral Image tool.</li>
<li>Added discrete Sibson interpolation tools (i.e. natural neighbour) for both 
 LiDAR specific data and for point data contained in Shapefiles.</li>
<li>Added the De-noise DEM tool.</li>
<li>Added the Reinitialize Attribute Table tool.</li>
<li>Added the Standard Deviation of Elevation tool.</li>
<li>Added the Isolate Ground Points (Lindsay's Method) tool for filtering LiDAR
 point clouds.</li>
<li>Added the Create Multiscale Topographic Position Image tool.</li>
<li>Added the Topological Breach Burn and FillBurn stream burning tools.</li>
<li>Modified tools that require calculating integral images to include a "number of
 significant decimal places" input. This allows the integral images to be 
 calculated using longs (instead of doubles) and reduces the likelihood of 
 numerical overflow errors for rasters with greater than two million grid cells.</li>
<li>Numerous other bug fixes and enhancements.</li>
</ul><]]>
            </Message>
        </Announcement>
    </Announcements>
</VersionInfo>
